fathomaway.com 2013-06-07

# Privacy Policy | FATHOM Travel Guides and Blog

## FATHOM Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of [Fathom Unlimited, Inc.] (“Fathom”, “we” or “us”) on the collection, use and disclosure of your information on [http://www.fathomaway.com](http://www.fathomaway.com/ "Fathom") (the “Site”) and the services, features, content or applications offered by Fathom (collectively with the Site, the “Services”). Fathom receives information about you from various sources, including: (i) if you register for the Site and the Services, through your user account with Fathom (your “Account”); (ii) your use of the Services generally; and (iii) from third party websites and services. When you use the Services, you are consenting to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, disclosure and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**What Does This Privacy Policy Cover?**

****This Privacy Policy covers the treatment of personally identifiable information (“ Personal Information”) gathered by Fathom when you are using or accessing the Services. This Privacy Policy also covers Fathom’s treatment of any Personal Information that Fathom’s business partners share with Fathom or that Fathom shares with its business partners.   

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Fathom does not own or control, including but not limited to any third party websites, services and applications (“Third Party Services”) that you elect to access through the Service or to individuals that Fathom does not manage or employ. While we attempt to facilitate access only to those Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access.

**What Information Does Fathom Collect?**

The information we gather enables us to personalize, improve and continue to operate the Services. In connection with certain aspects of the Services, we may request, collect and/or display some of your Personal Information. We collect the following types of information from our users.

_Sign-In Information:    
_When you create an Account, you will provide information that could be Personal Information, such as your username, password and email address. You acknowledge that this information may be personal to you, and by creating an account on Fathom and providing Personal Information to us, you allow others, including Fathom, to identify you and therefore may not be anonymous. We may use your contact information to send you information about our Services, but only rarely when we feel such information is important. You may unsubscribe from these messages through your Account settings, although Fathom regardless reserves the right to contact you when we believe it is necessary, such as for account recovery purposes.

_User Content:_  
Some features of the Services allow you to provide content to the Services, such as written comments. All content submitted by you to the Services may be retained by Fathom indefinitely, even after you terminate your account. We may continue to disclose such content to third parties in a manner that does not reveal Personal Information, as described in this Privacy Policy.

_IP Address Information and Other Information Collected Automatically:  
_ • Fathom automatically receives and records information from your web browser when you interact with the Services, including your IP address and cookie information. This information is used for fighting spam/malware and also to facilitate collection of data concerning your interaction with the Services (e.g., what links you have clicked on).

• Generally, the Services automatically collect usage information, such as the number and frequency of visitors to the Site. Fathom may use this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, but not in a manner that would identify you personally. This type of aggregate data enables us and third parties authorized by us to figure out how often individuals use parts of the Services so that we can analyze and improve them. 

_Email Communications:  
_ We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. We use this confirmation to improve our customer service.

_Information Collected Using Cookies:_  
• Cookies are pieces of text that may be provided to your computer through your web browser when you access a website. Your browser stores cookies in a manner associated with each website you visit. We use cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and tell us how and when you visit our Site and use the Services through the web. 

• Fathom cookies do not, by themselves, contain Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information to tell us who you are. As noted, however, we do use cookies to identify that your web browser has accessed aspects of the Services and may associate that information with your Account if you have one.  

• Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. We strongly recommend that you leave cookies active, because they enable you to take advantage the most attractive features of the Services.

• This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Fathom only and does not cover the use of cookies by third parties. Fathom does not control when or how third parties place cookies on your computer. For example, third party websites to which a link points may set cookies on your computer. 

_Aggregate Information:  
_ We collect statistical information about how both unregistered and registered users, collectively, use the Services (“Aggregate Information”). Some of this information is derived from Personal Information, such as your location (which, in turn, is derived from your IP address). This statistical information is not Personal Information and cannot be tied back to you, your Account or your web browser.

**How and To Whom Is My Information Shared?**

The Services are designed to help you share information with others. As a result, some of the information generated through the Services is shared publicly or with third parties.

_Public Fathom Activity Information:_  
Some of your activity on and through the Services is public by default. This includes, but is not limited to content you have posted on the Site or through the Services.

Registered users may have some of this information associated with their Accounts. Unregistered users will not have this association, but information concerning their use of the Services (such as what pages they have visited) is tracked anonymously through the use of cookies and stored by Fathom. 

Please also remember that if you choose to provide Personal Information using certain features of the Service, then that information is governed by the privacy settings of those particular features and may be publicly available. Individuals reading this information may use or disclose it to other individuals or entities without our control and without your knowledge. Therefore, we urge you to think carefully about including any specific information you may deem private in content that you create or submit through the Service.

_IP Address Information:_  
While we collect and store IP address information, that information is not made public. We do at times, however, share this information with our partners, service providers and other persons with whom we conduct business, but only to fight spam/malware. 

_Information You Elect to Share:_  
You may access other Third Party Services through the Services, for example by clicking on links to those Third Party Services from within Fathom. Fathom is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these Third Party Services, and you are responsible for reading and understanding those Third Party Services’ privacy policies. This Privacy Policy only governs information collected on the Services.

_Aggregate Information:_  
We share Aggregate Information with our partners, service providers and other persons with whom we conduct business. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners can understand how and how often people use our Services and their services or websites, which facilitates improving both their services and how Fathom interfaces with them. In addition, these third parties may share with us non-private, aggregated or otherwise non Personal Information about you that they have independently developed or acquired.

_Email Communications with Fathom:  
_ As part of the Services, you may occasionally receive from Fathom email and other communication relating to your Account. These emails will only be sent for purposes important to the Services, such as password recovery.

_User Profile Information:_    
User profile information including your username and other information you enter may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services. Users’ email addresses will not be directly revealed to other users by Fathom.

_Information Shared with Agents of Fathom:_    
We employ and contract with people and other entities that perform certain tasks on our behalf and who are under our control (our “Agents”). We may need to share Personal Information with our Agents in order to provide products or services to you. Unless we tell you differently, our Agents do not have any right to use Personal Information or other information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information with our Agents.

_Information Disclosed Pursuant to Business Transfers:_    
In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, if Fathom, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Fathom goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Fathom may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy.

_Information Disclosed for the Protection of Fathom and Others:_    
Fathom also reserves the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information as it reasonably believes is necessary to (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (ii) enforce these Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations hereof, (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, (iv) respond to user support requests, or (v) protect the rights, property or safety of Fathom, its users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam/malware prevention.

_Information We Share With Your Consent:_    
Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information.

**Is Information About Me Secure?  **

Your Account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You need to prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

Fathom endeavors to protect Account information to ensure that it is kept private; however, Fathom cannot guarantee the security of any Account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. 

Fathom otherwise stores all of its information, including your IP address information, using industry-standard security techniques. Fathom does not guarantee or warrant that such techniques will prevent unauthorized access to information about you stored by Fathom, Personal Information or otherwise.

**What Information of Mine Can I Access?**

****If you are a registered user, you can access information associated with your Account by logging into the Site. Registered and unregistered users can access and delete cookies through their web browser settings.

**How Can I Delete My Account?**  

Should you ever decide to delete your Account, you may do so by emailing [help@fathomaway.com](mailto:help@fathomaway.com). If you terminate your Account, any association between your Account and information stored by Fathom will no longer be accessible through your Account. However, given the nature of sharing using Fathom, any public activity on your Account prior to deletion will remain stored on Fathom’s servers and will remain accessible to the public.

**What Choices Do I Have Regarding My Information?**

****• You can use many of the features of the service without registering, thereby limiting the type of information that we collect.

• As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose certain information to Fathom, even though it may be needed to take advantage of some Fathom features.

• You can delete your Account. Please note that Fathom will need to verify that you have the authority to delete the Account, and activity generated prior to deletion will remain stored by Fathom and may be publicly accessible.  

**What Happens When There Are Changes to this Privacy Policy?**

****Fathom may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Services or sending you an email. A user is bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the Services after such changes have been first posted.

**What If I Have Questions or Concerns?**  

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy using the Services, please send us a detailed message to [help@fathomaway.com](mailto:help@fathomaway.com). We will make every effort to resolve your concerns.

**Effective Date:**  April 10, 2011. **  
**
